EPHANTUS OKUMU

412, KITENGELA - NAIROBI

+254713197824 # EPHANTOKUMU98@GMAIL.COM # GITHUB.COM/EPHANTUSOKUMU

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in all levels of testing, including performance, functional, integration, system, regression, and user acceptance testing. Supportive and enthusiastic team player dedicated to streamlining processes and efficiently resolving project issues.

Sound knowledge of PHP, JavaScript, Java and related frameworks – Laravel, ReactJS, NodeJS. MongoDB, MySQL, SQL, MariaDB, CSS, HTML5, Bootstrap, React Strap, material UI and C#

Skill Highlights

- Agile/Scrum methodology
- Performance and scalability
- Frontend Development
- Deployment and Hosting

- Search Engine Optimization
- API design
- Backend Development

Experience

Assistant Software Engineer II (Contract) - 09/2019 to 08/2020

Kenya School of Government – Mombasa Campus

- Investigation, design, and implement scalable applications for data identification, analysis, retrieval, and indexing.
- Software design and development while remaining concentrate on client needs.
- Cooperate diligently with other IT team members to plan, design, and develop smart solutions.
- Estimate interface between hardware and software.
- Interface with business analysts, developers, and technical support to determine optimal specifications.

Software Developer (Contract) - 01/2019 to 08/2019 **Switch TV, Nairobi.**

- Analysis, design, coding, testing and implementation of computer programs
- Creating a backup and recovery strategy for the database, and regularly testing the backups.
- Primary and disaster recovery data centers
- Planning for and allocating the database system's physical requirements.
- Modifying the database structure using information provided by application developers.
- Software design and development while remaining concentrate on client needs.
- Cooperate diligently with other IT team members to plan, design, and develop smart solutions.
- Estimate interface between hardware and software.
- Interface with business analysts, developers, and technical support to determine optimal specifications.

Software Engineer Intern - 07/2018 to 12/2018 **InterIntel Technologies, Nairobi**

- Software design and development while remaining concentrate on client needs.
- Planning for and allocating the database system's physical requirements.

- Modifying the database structure using information provided by application developers.
- Interface with business analysts, developers, and technical support to determine optimal specifications.

Practical Attachment - 09/2017 to 12/2017 **Snettscom Innovative Solutions, Kisumu**

- Consulted regularly with customers on project status, proposals and technical issues.
- Transformed existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces, and improve efficiency.
- Cooperate diligently with other IT team members to plan, design, and develop smart solutions.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Informatics (2 nd CLA Moi University, Eldoret	ASS Honours, Upper Division) -	2013 - 2018
Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Agoro Oyombe Secondary School, Siaya	B+	2009 – 2012
Kenya Certificate of Primary Education Ng'iya Mixed Primary School	B +	2001- 2008

Key Achievements

Web Systems and Apps:

- 1. Switch TV Web App and Livestreaming System www.switchtv.ke
- 2. React/Next JS Online Store www.react-reserve.sh
- 3. Wildpro Adventures Website <u>www.wildroadventures.co.ke</u>
- 4. Frontend Design of the Switch TV android Mobile App
- 5. Development and maintenance of client Web APPs
- 6. List of Projects Done https://github.com/ephantusokumu?tab=repositories

Referees

Mr. Richard Ndonye Software Development Manager – Kenya Red Cross / Switch TV Mobile: 0721834050

ndonyengungu@gmail.com

Jael Maza

IT and Software Development Officer – KSG Mombasa

Mobile: +254728240839 mazajael@gmail.com

Jeremy Ndidi

Mobile Apps Developer, Switch TV

Mobile: 0727399505 jerrydindi@gmail.com